<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Entrepreneurship | Ampirik Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ampirik.github.io/blog/categories/entrepreneurship/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ampirik.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-26T21:53:50+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://ampirik.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ampirik]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://ampirik.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/first-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-25T22:45:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://ampirik.github.io/blog/2013/06/25/first-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Me and Edu are two guys who met in uni when studying Computer Engineering back in 2004.
Over the years our friendship has grown to a point where our common friends
usually tease us by saying we have a bromance.
I don&rsquo;t blame them, we have many interests in common and we see life from a similar perspective.
Nowadays we both work as software engineers for the same company in Stockholm, Sweden.</p>

<p>We are two human beings who strive to evolve and to become better at several things we like.
Learning is our favorite tool to meet this need.
For us, one of the best joys in life is to read about something new, understand it and
apply it to our daily activities.
It just feels so good whenever you, in the middle of the learning process,
stop for a second and become aware of that moment.
It also feels wonderful to look back in time and see everything you have learned and
how your personality has evolved in the last months.</p>

<p>Furthermore, we are two individuals with tons of initiative inside of us.
Our brains are filled with exciting ideas that we would like to try out,
projects that, rather than just being cool or having the potential of making loads of money,
are meaningful to us and fit our personalities.
We enjoy tremendously working on such projects,
taking a simple idea all the way to something concrete that us and others find useful.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, our current lifestyle is very far from what is described above.
Even though we are employed by a great company with fantastic co-workers and a friendly atmosphere,
the truth is that we have learned and evolved very little in the last months,
most of the tasks we perform are fairly mechanical and usually we
execute a roadmap decided by the management of the company.
Very far from our ideals.
Therefore, we try to have our needs met after work and during the weekends.
But considering that we spend around fifty hours per week working and commuting
and that our job is very mentally demanding,
it is very hard to find the time and the energy during weekdays to satisfy our needs.
In the weekends, we might manage to squeeze in some short learning sessions,
but we mainly focus on spending quality time with our partners, family and friends,
resting and doing housekeeping tasks.</p>

<p>Even though we are fairly happy with our current lives we feel that it could be much better.
Now, at our age of 27, it is a perfect time to try to change how things are.
Therefore, we are determined to find an economically sustainable lifestyle where learning,
purpose, meaningfulness and excitement are as present as possible.</p>

<p>We will be telling you a bit more about our trip in the coming weeks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
